深入研究一下
Take a deeper look at the theory that
作为抽象数据类型的基础。
underlies abstract data types.
它本身不仅优雅有趣，
It's not only elegant and interesting in its own right,
但它具有直接的实际应用价值
but it has immediate practical application
设计一个ADT的实现。
to design an implementation of an ADT.
您将能够构建更好的抽象数据类型，
You'll be able to build better abstract data types,
而且你也不太可能落入微妙的陷阱。
and you'll be less likely to fall into subtle traps.
现在我们要考虑两人之间的关系
Now we're going to think about the relationship between two
价值空间。
spaces of values.
第一个空间称为表示值的空间或表示
First space is called the space of representation values or rep
简称值。
values for short.
这些是实际实现实体的值。
And these are the values of the actual implementation entities.
所以在简单的情况下，抽象数据类型
So in simple cases, an abstract data type
我们只实现了一个对象。
we implemented as just a single object.
但更常见的是，需要一个小的物体网络，
But more commonly, a small network of objects is needed,
所以这个值实际上是
so this value is actually often something
更复杂。
rather more complicated.
不过，现在我们要简单地考虑一下
For now, though, we'll think about it simply
作为一个数学值。
as a mathematical value.
所以一个表示值。
So a representation value.
还有一个抽象值的空间
And then there is a space of abstract values
包含类型为
that consists of the values that the type is
专为支撑而设计。
designed to support.
这是我们想象的虚构，
These are a figment of our imaginations,
不存在的柏拉图实体
the platonic entities that don't exist exactly
如前所述，但这是我们想要的
as described, but are the way we want
思考或观察抽象类型的元素
to think about or viewing the elements of the abstract type
当你是这种类型的客户时。
when you are a client of the type.
例如，整个整数集的抽象类型
For example, an abstract type for the whole set of integers
可能有数学整数作为它的抽象值空间，
might have mathematical integers as its abstract value space,
但事实上
but the fact that it might be implemented
是基元有界整数的数组
is an array of primitive, bounded ints
与类型的用户没有实际关系。
is not really relevant to the user of the type.
这实际上是Java中一个大整数的内部内容。
This is what's actually inside a big integer in Java.
但这种类型的用户想考虑一下
But the user of the type wants to think of it
就像一组数学整数，通常是
just as the set of mathematical integers, which is usually
叫Z。所以这就是区别
called Z. So that's the difference
在表示值和抽象值之间。
between representation values and abstract values.
我们很快就会看到更多的例子。
We'll see some more examples soon.
当然，现在抽象类型的实现者
Now, of course, the implementer of the abstract type
必须对表示值感兴趣，
has to be interested in the representation values,
因为实现者的工作
since the implementer's job to achieve
抽象价值空间的幻象
the illusion of the abstract value space
使用rep值空间。
using the rep value space.
例如，假设我们想
So suppose, for example, that we want to represent
一组字符。
a set of characters.
这是我们的抽象数据类型。
That's our abstract data type.
这是一个角色集。
It's a character set.
我们选择使用一个字符串，一系列字符，
And we choose to use a string, a sequence of characters,
代表它。
to represent it.
那么rep空间R包含字符串。
Then the rep space R contains strings.
它实际上包含这些字符集对象
It contains actually these char set objects
里面有一个指向字符串的字段
that have inside them a field pointing to a string
然后，当然，那个string对象指向其他东西。
and then, of course, that string object points to other things.
但我们要把它缩写一下
But we're just going to abbreviate it
通过说，嗯，这是一系列的字符
by saying, well, it's a sequence of characters
它应该代表一组字符。
that is supposed to represent a set of characters.
所以我们可以用图形的方式显示这两个值空间
So we can show those two value spaces graphically
从rep值到抽象值有一个弧
with an arc from a rep value to the abstract value
它代表。
it represents.
这是R，rep空间，它包含字符串。
This is R, the rep space, and it contains strings.
这是一个抽象的空间，
And this is A, the abstract space,
它包含一组字符。
and it contains sets of characters.
注意花括号。
Notice the curly braces.
这张照片有几点需要注意。
Now there's several things to note about this picture.
首先，每个抽象值
First of all, every abstract value
由某个rep值映射到，因此为空集
is mapped to by some rep value, so empty set
由空字符串映射。
is mapped by the empty string.
这组字符ABC被映射
This set of characters, ABC, is mapped
至少是弦乐，ABC，还有其他的。
to by at least the string, ABC, but others, as well.
实现抽象类型的目的
The purpose of implementing the abstract type
支持对抽象值的操作，
is to support operations on abstract values,
所以我们应该
so presumably then, we need to be
能够创造和操纵所有可能的A，所以他们必须
able to create and manipulate all possible A's, so they must
可以用一些R来表示。
be representable by some R.
现在一些抽象值可以由多个rep映射到
Now some abstract values may be mapped to by more than one rep
值，当表示不是
value, and this can happen when the representation isn't
编码那么紧。
that tight in coding.
表示无序集的方法可能不止一种
There may be more than one way to represent an unordered set
作为字符串的字符。
of characters as a string.
但也许并不是所有的值都被映射。
But maybe not all of their values are mapped.
所以，在这种情况下，我们与ABBC没有优势。
So, in this case, we don't have an edge from ABBC.
它没有映射。
It's not mapped.
我们已经决定字符串不应该包含重复项，
We've decided that the string should not contain duplicates,
当我们写作的时候，比如说，
and that will allow us, when we're writing, for example,
此字符集数据类型的remove方法，
the remove method for this char set data type,
我们只要停下来
we'll be able to just stop as soon as we
找到要移除的角色的第一个实例，
find the first instance of a character to remove,
因为我们知道最多只能有一个。
since we know there can be at most one.
实际上，我们只能说明几个要素
In practice, we can only illustrate a few elements
在他们关系中的这两个空间中，
of these two spaces in their relationships,
作为一个整体的图形是无限的。
as the graph as a whole is infinite.
所以我们要用两件事来描述它。
So we're going to describe it by giving two things.
首先是映射rep的抽象函数
First is an abstraction function that maps rep
值到它们所表示的抽象值。
values to the abstract values they represent.
这里的弧是抽象函数。
So the arcs here are the abstraction function.
现在用函数的术语来说，
Now in the terminology of functions,
我们上面讨论过的性质
the properties we discussed above
可以说函数是满射的
can be expressed by saying that the function is surjective
或者到——这意味着映射的每个抽象值
or onto-- that means every abstract values mapped
以某种代表性的价值。
to by some rep value.
但不一定是双射的。
But it's not necessarily bijective.
所以可能有多个抽象的rep值
So there may be multiple abstract rep values that
映射到相同的抽象值。
map to the same abstract value.
它通常是部分的，所以不是
And it's often partial, so it's not
在其整个域上定义。
defined on its entire domain.
并不是rep空间中的所有值都被映射。
Not all the values here in the rep space are mapped.
所以我有阻塞功能。
So I have an obstruction function.
我们还有一个rep变量，它将rep值映射到布尔值。
We also have a rep variant that maps rep values to a Boolean.
代表不变量，代表不变量，意味着什么
And what the rep invariant, the representation invariant, means
当rep值的RVI为真时，如果
is that when RVI of a rep value is true if
只有当R被抽象函数映射时。
and only if R is mapped by the abstraction functions.
所以RI告诉我们一个给定的rep值的格式是否正确。
So RI tells us whether a given rep value is well-formed.
或者，你可以把RI看作一个集合。
Alternatively, you can think of the RI as a set.
它是定义AF的rep值的子集。
It's a subset of rep values on which the AF is defined.
这是R的rep不变子集。
So this is the rep invariant subset of R.
现在我们要写下rep不变量
Now we want to write down the rep invariant
在代码的抽象函数中，
in the abstract function in the code,
就在我们写下销售代表的地方。
right next to where we write down the rep itself.
所以我们把这里的代表写成了一个字符串。
So we wrote down the rep here as a string.
它的代表不变量说
And its rep invariant says that it's
不包含重复字符的字符串。
a string that contains no repeated characters.
所以这说明这是被排除在外的。
So that's stating that this is excluded.
这是违法的。
This is illegal.
然而，这些都是法律陈述。
Whereas, these are legal representations.
所以把它想象成，
So think about this as being like,
有点像，不变量。
kind of like, an invariant.
它是所有价值观，法律价值观的不变量，
It is an invariant on all values, on legal values,
属于这种抽象数据类型。
of this abstract data type.
它必须在程序的所有状态下都是正确的。
It must always be true in all states of the program.
然后抽象函数
And then the abstraction function
说明特定代表值的映射方式
states how a particular rep value S maps
一个特定的抽象值。
to a particular abstract value.
在这种情况下，我们只是用英语写，
And in this case, again, we're just writing it in English,
值S表示在S中找到的字符集。
a value S represents the set of characters that are found in S.
现在关于抽象函数和
Now a common confusion about abstraction functions and rep
不变性是一旦你有了代表--
invariance is that once you have the rep--
一旦你有了代表空间和抽象值
once you have rather the rep space and the abstract value
空间——这完全决定了抽象
space-- and that fully determines the abstraction
rep不变量中的函数——这不是真的。
function in the rep invariant-- that's not true.
如果那是真的，那么这些想法就没什么用处了
If that were true, then these ideas would be of little use
因为他们有多余的东西
since they'd be redundant with something which was
其他地方已经有了。
already available elsewhere.
抽象值空间本身并不
The abstract value space alone does not
确定其中任何一个。
determine either one of them.
可以有几个表示
There can be several representations
对于相同的抽象类型。
for the same abstract type.
我们不一定要用字符串来表示
We don't necessarily have to use strings to represent
一组字符。
a set of characters.
我们可以用一个位向量，一个位数组，
We could conceivably use a bit vector, an array of bits,
每个可能的字符有1位
with 1-bit for each possible character
在字符数据类型中。
that we have in the character data type.
显然，我们需要两个不同的抽象函数
Clearly we would need two different abstraction functions
映射这两个非常不同的rep值空间。
to map these two very different rep value spaces.
现在不那么明显了为什么，
Now it's a little less obvious why,
如果你选择了这两个空间，
if once you've chosen both of these spaces,
你没有决心，没有完全确定的抽象概念
you don't have a determination, a fully determined abstraction
rep不变量的函数，但关键是
function of rep invariant, but the key point
是不是为rep定义了一个类型，比如string--
is that defining a type for the rep, like string--
那就是为rep值选择空间--
and that's choosing the space for the rep values--
不确定哪个rep值
does not determine which of the rep values
将被视为合法。
will be deemed to be legal.
以及那些合法的，确切地说
And of those that are legal, exactly how
他们会被解释的。
they'll be interpreted.
所以与其像我们上面所做的那样决定，
So rather than deciding, as we did above,
字符串不能有重复项
that strings can have no duplicates-- alll right-- that
我们的代表在这里是不变的--我们可以，
was our rep invariant here-- we could, instead,
允许重复，但同时
allow duplicates, but at the same time
要求对字符进行排序，显示
require that the characters be sorted, appearing
以非递减的顺序。
in non-decreasing order.
这是一个非常不同的代表不变量。
That's a very different rep invariant.
这个rep不变量的优点
And the advantage of this rep invariant
现在我们可以做一个更快的查找操作。
is now we can do a much faster find operation.
我们可以用对数来检查集合的成员资格，
We can check membership in the set in logarithmic,
而不是线性时间，使用二进制搜索。
rather than linear time, using binary search.
所以这是相同的rep值空间。
So it's the same rep value space.
还是一根绳子。
It's still a string.
但是它有一个不同的rep不变量。
But it has a different rep invariant.
现在即使rep值的类型相同
Now even with the same type for the rep value
空间和相同的rep不变量RI，
space and the same rep invariant RI,
我们还是可以用不同的方式来解释
we still might interpret the rep differently
使用不同的抽象函数AF。
with a different abstraction functions AF.
假设我们有一个rep不变量
So suppose we have a rep invariant that admits
任何字符串。
any string of characters.
然后我们可以定义AF，如上所述，来表示
Then we can define AF, as above, to represent
数组元素作为集合的元素。
the arrays elements as the elements of the set.
但没有优先考虑的理由
But there is no A priority reason
让代表决定解释。
to let the rep decide the interpretation.
例如，我们可以解释连续对
For example, maybe we could interpret consecutive pairs
作为子范围的字符，因此字符串rep，ACGG，是
of characters as sub ranges, so that the string rep, ACGG, is
解释为两个范围对，A到C，G到G。
interpreted as two range pairs, A through C, and G through G.
因此，代表一个集合，ABCG。
And, therefore, represents a set, ABCG.
所以我和空军会
So here's what the AF and I would look
就像那个代表。
like for that representation.
rep不变量要求长度为偶数。
The rep invariant would require that length is even.
一切正常。
And that it's in order.
然后抽象函数
And then the abstraction function
会说它代表着山脉的结合
would say it represents the union of the ranges
从I的S开始，I的S加1，
starting from S of I, S of I plus 1,
对于S中的每个相邻字符对。
for each adjacent pair of characters in S.
中心点是设计一个抽象类型
The central point is that designing an abstract type
意思不仅仅是选择这两个空间，抽象值
means not only choosing these two spaces, the abstract value
规范的空间和rep值
space for the specification, and the rep value
实施的空间，也决定了
space for the implementation, but also deciding
使用什么rep值，以及如何解释它们。
what rep values to use, and how to interpret them.
写下来是非常重要的
It's critically important to write down
正如我们在上面所做的，你的代码中的这些假设，
these assumptions in your code, as we've done above,
所以未来的程序员，尤其是你未来的自我，
so that future programmers, and especially your future self,
知道表示的实际含义。
are aware of what the representation actually means.
为什么呢？
Now why is that?
如果不同的实现者不同意
What happens if different implementers disagree
关于代表的意思？
about the meaning of the rep?
让我们在练习中探索一下。
Let's explore that in the exercises.